JHON DEIBER DIAZ PARRA | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Montréal QC, Canada | (514)3461672 | jhondeiberd@gmail.com Portfolio Linkedin Github

PROFILE

Professional with extensive skills and experience in industry, I have experience in Microsoft Dynamics ERP, systems such as POS, eCommerce, WMS, and PLM for 12 years, SQL database server for 3 years. I know different programming languages and tools that allow me to be a person capable of contributing to the needs of the company and its customers. Throughout my career, I have participated in large-scale complex projects, functionalities, and interfaces reengineering. I believe that innovation and continuous improvement is a success factor for organizations. which is why I tirelessly insist on applying these criteria in all the initiatives in which I have participated. I like to make a difference with my commitment, my responsibility, and my effort, and always give my best.

SKILLS & OTHER

Web HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Web services API, REST, MVC

Programming languages Java, Python, GO, C#, C++, PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, T-SQL, Android -Kotlin, Flutter

Control version Git. GitHub. Bitbucket

Project management Agile Methodology, Scrum, Kamban, Trello, Slack

Framework ASP.NET core, React.js, Express.Js

Database SQL server (T-SQL), MySql, MariaBD, PostgreSQL, SSIS, ETL, Data warehouse

Business Software ERP Microsoft Dynamics, WMS Arcante, PLM Porini, ICG POS

Soft skills Office 365 (Excel, Word, Windows), PowerShell, XML, J-son, Object Oriented

Programming (OOP)

Other skills Teamwork, creative problem solving, attention to detail, philomath.

PROJECTS

Application personal Budget Android

Application Kottlin Android to handle a personal budget, where the user adds income, expenses and as a result shows a personal balance. It allows adding, editing, deleting transactions and is multilingual.

Environment: Kottlin Android

Environment: Node.js, ReactJs, PostgreSQL

Associated with: ISI College Team users: Jhon Diaz **Code**

Application full-stack Manager favorite music albums

Development of a web application for the user to control your list of favorites, searching, adding, and deleting. It was built with a Back-end server using Node is add Express for the REST APIs that manage the PostgreSQL database. The Front-end server is a React is that request the user requirements with RESTful APIs for the Discogs Music. My role in this project was developing the Back-end part.

Associated with: ISI College Team users: Anuj Narang and Jhon Diaz Code

MVC application for managing contacts

Environment: C# Application C# for contact management, a graphical interface that allows you to create new contacts, edit existing ones and delete them, these data are stored in text files. In this project worked. In this project, we worked on distributing parts of the menu for the project. In this project, we distributed parts of the menu for the project, and each one coded and tested his part.

Associated with: ISI College Team users: Ricardo Castano and Jhon Diaz

Administrador de la base de datos ERP **Environment:** SQL server

Developed in Transact-SQL reports and consulting for information analysis and decision-making, creation, reconstruction and reorganization of indexes and update statistics, backups to maintain optimal performance of the company's ERP database.

Associated with: ISI College

EDUCATION

Institut Supérieur d'Informatique - Montreal, Canada

2021- Present

Programming and Web Technologies, Attestation of College Studies

Centre Social d'aide aux Immigrants - CSAI - Montreal, Canada

Francisation Level 4, French studies

2022 - Present

Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas, Bogotá - Colombia

2008 - 2013

Production engineer, Bachelor's Degree

English Spanish Spanish Spanish Spanish Spanish CERTIFICATIONS

Lourtec IT Services and IT Consulting - Online

Lourtec IT Services and IT Consulting – Online

Analyzing data with Power BI, Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)

SQL 2016 Database Development, Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)

Developing C# - ASP.NET Core MVC, Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)

2020 - 2020

2019 - 2020

2019 - 2019

Fundación Carlos Slim - Online

Object-oriented programming paradigm

Database Administrator (DBA)

2021 - 2021

2017 - 2018

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

Applications and Database Manager ERP

2017 - 2020

- Implemented agile methodologies for execution and follow-up of projects and developments in Dynamics ERP.
- Supported my team with debugging code in the Dynamics ERP AOT for bug fixes.
- Developed database queries for incident resolution and analysis.
- Monitored the database performance, defined users and enabled the data distribution.
- Database maintenance, indexes, re-indexing, statistics, locks, back-up
- Collaborated with area managers and third-level service companies to identify and resolve problems, coordinated system requirements and created project schedules.
- Planned and executed annual budget for ERP improvement.
- Planned, implemented and supervised IT technology solutions to ensure satisfactory fulfillment of end-user requirements, implementation and support in a productive environment.
- Coordinated the created of virtual training material for the users' application

OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Boardwalk, Montréal QC, Canada

Landscaper

2021 - Present

- Responsible for painting common areas of assigned buildings.
- Responsible for mowing the lawns around the buildings.
- Support the maintenance and concierges teams when necessary.

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

Applications Professional ERP

2008 - 2017

- Escalated problems to the Technical Specialist Level III's or above within the support structure.
- Led the definition and formation of plans for applications aimed to master users' knowledge.
- Performed test runs for approval and implementation of developments in a production environment.
- Enhanced and maintained ERP functionalities and execute upcoming projects.
- Implemented and deployed ERP's standard modules and local functionalities.
- · Optimized processes and procedures in the ERP
- Trained the different ERP users in the ERP modules.

Production Planning Analyst

2006 - 2008

- Implemented Material Requirements Planning (MRP) methodology for product production
- Designed and configured technical sheets and spreadsheets for clothing products.
- Calculated the manufacturing route and the cost of the bill of materials for the garments.
- Applied engineering industrialization methods and plans to improve the manufacturing process to optimize operating costs.
- Optimized raw material inventories and allocation based on collection designs.

Production Engineering Analyst

2003 - 2006

- Designed and enhance workload balancing for production plants.
- Implemented engineering methods and time analysis for the plans' workstations.
- Designed and implement standards time for garments operations.
- Identified and improved bottlenecks for production modules.
- Prepared efficiency reports and control the unproductive time of the plant.